<task>
  <title>Fix chat route to use graph-interpreter (enables AGENT_URL backend agent flow)</title>

  <context>
    <project>Chatbot-temp — React + Hono + MongoDB chat UI with graph-based backend agent</project>
    <problem>
      The chat route at backend/src/routes/chat.ts currently calls Gemini DIRECTLY with getGeminiAnswer(userText),
      bypassing the graph-interpreter service entirely. This means:
      1. The backend agent (AGENT_URL) is NEVER called from this route
      2. Without GEMINI_API_KEY, it returns 502 error instead of raw agent response
      3. Conversation history is NOT forwarded to the agent
      4. Image support is NOT wired up in this route
    </problem>
    <solution>
      Refactor the chat route to use interpretGraph() from graph-interpreter.ts instead of direct Gemini calls.
      This enables the full pipeline: AGENT_URL → graph data → Gemini interpretation → natural text.
      It also enables the existing bypass: when GEMINI_API_KEY is missing, raw agent JSON is returned to UI.
    </solution>
  </context>

  <files>
    <primary>backend/src/routes/chat.ts</primary>
    <reference>backend/src/services/graph-interpreter.ts</reference>
  </files>

  <requirements>
    <req id="1">Replace direct getGeminiAnswer() call with interpretGraph() from graph-interpreter</req>
    <req id="2">Load conversation history from MongoDB and pass it to interpretGraph()</req>
    <req id="3">Keep the existing user message persistence logic unchanged</req>
    <req id="4">Keep the auto-title logic unchanged</req>
    <req id="5">Handle errors properly: 502 for agent errors, preserve existing error format</req>
    <req id="6">Remove unused imports: GoogleGenerativeAI, the geminiModel, getGeminiAnswer function</req>
    <req id="7">Remove the entire TEMPLATE rollback block (commented-out code) — it is dead weight</req>
    <req id="8">Do NOT change any other routes or files</req>
  </requirements>

  <implementation-details>
    <detail>Import: import { interpretGraph } from '../services/graph-interpreter.js'</detail>
    <detail>Load history: const history = await Message.find({ conversationId: convId }).sort({ createdAt: 1 }).lean()</detail>
    <detail>Filter history: exclude the current user message we just saved (filter by createdAt >= now or by id)</detail>
    <detail>Call: const answer = await interpretGraph(userText, historyItems, convId)</detail>
    <detail>HistoryItems type: Array<{ role: 'user' | 'assistant', content: string }></detail>
  </implementation-details>

  <constraints>
    <constraint>Do NOT modify graph-interpreter.ts</constraint>
    <constraint>Do NOT modify any other route files</constraint>
    <constraint>Do NOT change API response format — must still return { role: 'assistant', content: answer, title: conv.title }</constraint>
    <constraint>Keep the file under 200 lines after changes</constraint>
  </constraints>

  <verification>
    <step>Run: cd backend && npm run build — must compile without errors</step>
    <step>Run: cd backend && npx tsc --noEmit — no type errors</step>
    <step>Verify: POST /api/conversations/:id/chat returns assistant response</step>
    <step>Verify: Without GEMINI_API_KEY, returns raw JSON string from agent</step>
  </verification>
</task>
